remember Letterman and Asadi, the child king and his mother guarded like hostages at some fall.
With Bahamas gone, no one will be watching them.
I want to get them out and I could use your help.
Kidnapping the Sun, King of the Shadow Kharja is no small task.
It's not kidnapping.
They want to go to Meridian to safety.
How do you know that?
I've been posing as the Saudis Handmaiden.
She's scared for herself off course, but mostly for Letterman.
Why do you care what happens to them?
A demon is the Shadow Cardiges.
Figurehead.
If he defects, it will remove their last trace of legitimacy.
Beyond that, he's just a boy who clings to his mommy.
What do you need to get in a Saudi?
And it'll turn out of sinful sun.
Fall is the easy part.
I'll handle that.
The big fuss will be crossing the border to the Sunday Um,
find my friend three Toho.
I'd evening the branded shore.
I heart his crew to sweep the path.
So all you have to do is wait for me
You're Three-Toed Huadiv right? Vanasha sent me. What happened?
I got hornswoggled, that's what.
Vanasha batted her lashes, wiggled her hips, and promised us treasure.
"Clear a path for the royals," she said.
"Sneak past the garrison and skewer a few Watchers, hardly a bother."
Little did we know there was a damned monstrosity lurking underground.
When will I learn not to gawk at skinny girls?
Why do you think Vanasha swindled you?
My crew came to Sunfall because we heard the bounties were fat.
She offered us the fattest one of all, enough to retire on.
Find the best path to the lake, make sure it's safe.
What could go wrong? Turns out a lot!
Like bloody murder in the grinding jaws of a heinous death beast!
I wondered why the Shadow Carja didn't pay attention to the pass.
Well, they don't need to, a rock eating demon guards it for them.
It tunnels in the dirt, breaks through the earth, and blast rocks from it's stinking face!
I barely escaped, my comrades weren't so lucky.
I might shed a tear if they weren't all cut-throats and cheaters.
Vanasha will be here soon with Nasadi and Itamen.
I've got to destroy that thing in the pass before they arrive.
You're not too bright, are you?
Well, we didn't last long against it but I'll tell you what I know.
It has armour everywhere, a little less at the rear.
And when it goes underground, it will lose track of you if you're quiet.
I need to get going.
I promise to look solemn at your funeral before I hit the bar.
I'll tuck that away.
Then we do it the hard way.
It felt that!
Saving these for the trail.
HUADIV: By the radiant Sun, I can't believe it!
HUADIV: I thought that evil rock chewer would grind you up.
HUADIV: After that miracle, all we can do is wait.
HUADIV: Vanasha will be here soon, along with a boat that will take the royals across the lake.
VANASHA: Ah, little huntress, glad you accepted my invitation to play bodyguard.
VANASHA: Where are your men Huadiv?
VANASHA: It looks like something chewed you up and spat you out.
HUADIV: That's pretty much exactly what happened.
ALOY: The way is clear. Can we go?
VANASHA: I like how you always cut to the chase, in this case literally.
VANASHA: It won't be long before we're followed.
VANASHA: Don't be afraid, your radiance. We've got excellent protection.
VANASHA: Oh, dear. Here come the Shadow Carja and they're very angry with me.
ALOY: I'll hold them off!
VANASHA: Very noble of you but when I started fuss, I like to finish it.
VANASHA: Not that your assistance isn't welcome.
VANASHA: Huadiv, get Itamen and his mother to the shore, carefully.
VANASHA: So it comes to this.
VANASHA: I must say, after two years under the heel of these zealots, I'm ready to extract a little blood.
VANASHA: Some traps would be nice.
VANASHA: Damn, just missed!
VANASHA: Let's try something new, shall we?
VANASHA: Well, that was entertaining, but I suspect we're not done.
VANASHA: More of the bastards, get ready.
VANASHA: Well now, seems I've worked up a bit of a sweat.
VANASHA: I don't want to jinx it, but we might be in the clear.
VANASHA: A bit late aren't we gentlemen?
CARJA: Sorry, ma'am, the boat— [roaring]
VANASHA: Damn, I spoke too soon.
ALOY: This one's mine. Get to the boat.
VANASHA: You know, this time I think I might be out of my league.
VANASHA: If anything happens to her, I will be very cross.
CARJA: We're not going anywhere.
CARJA: Oh no!
ALOY: Try me now.
ALOY: She went that-a-way!
VANASHA: Not exactly a royal barge, is it?
VANASHA: Ah well, defectors can't be choosers.
VANASHA: Let's get aboard, shall we?
VANASHA: You've done a good thing, maybe even ended a war.
ALOY: Maybe. But my war just keeps going.
AVAD: Itamen, my brother, welcome home. You have nothing to fear.
AVAD: You are now under the protection of the Sundom, my protection.
AVAD: As is your mother. She will not be harmed, you have my word, the law of the Sun.
AVAD: Aloy. It seems I see your influence everywhere.
AVAD: You've done so much for the Sundom and it will always be appreciated.
AVAD: You have my thanks. May you walk in the light.
VANASHA: Appalling.
VANASHA: I spend two years in the Forbidden West setting this up and the redhead gets all the credit?
HUADIV: I'm still getting paid, right?
VANASHA: You'll be lucky if I let you live.
VANASHA: I couldn't have done this without you.
VANASHA: When we meet again, I'll give you a proper thanks, I promise.
MERCHANT: Don't pass up these goods!
MERCHANT: Fine goods for a fair price.
CARJA: You wouldn't believe–
MERCHANT: It won't cost you a shard just to look.
MERCHANT: Don't pass up these goods.
MERCHANT: Take a look at these wares.
GUARD: Damn Oseram stirring up tensions. I'm keeping my eyes open.
CARJA: I keep thinking about my sister in the Sundom—
CARJA: Ah, I've had enough of work.
GUARD: It's always the ones you least expect that cause you trouble.
CARJA: …last night, so it's good to just take a breather.
CARJA: I'm a guard, not the town crier.
MERCHANT: You'll regret not stopping when—
NOBLE: Is that really all you have? It won't do at all.
MERCHANT: Buy what you need, leave the rest.
MERCHANT: You'll regret not stopping.
TALANAH: Hawk Bradavin Khane Padish, cherished brother.
TALANAH: And Sunhawk Talavad Khane Padish, beloved father.
TALANAH: Let their memory and sacrifice be a beacon for all hunters, all people to follow.
Look, a memorial to my father and brother, and all the men who died in the Sun-Ring.
You made this possible Aloy. Thank you.
What was that prayer you were saying when I first came in? I didn't hear all of it.
O Great Sun, make treaty with the moon to give our fallen quiet rest.
Furnish them with the armour of your brazen heat.
Give them shafts of sunlight for spears.
Illuminate the path to the skies for each one of them.
Hawk Gravid Khane Morza.
Hawk Sirav Khane Pir.
Hawk Yusalin Khane Jageer.
Hawk Khulasiv Khane Sovaliy.
Hawk Bradavin Khane Padish, cherished brother.
And Sunhawk Talavad Khane Padish, beloved father.
Let their memory and sacrifice be a beacon for all hunters, all people to follow.
What happens now in the lodge?
As Sunhawk I've made sure we invite prospective members based on ability and drive.
Regardless of Carja blood.
This lodge will be a stale bastion of the old regime no longer.
So what's it like to be Sunhawk?
It feels like sunrise after a long night.
I'm in your debt.
You'll always have a special home here, if you want it.
Well, congratulations Talanah. I should get going.
Thank you Aloy Despite the Nora.
[laughs]
May you always take your prey.
CARJA: Spies have released Prince Itamen from Sunfall!
MERCHANT: These aren't goods, they're necessities!
MERCHANT: You'll regret not stopping—
CARJA: Dervahl should die for his crimes.
CARJA: You do little—
MERCHANT: Buy what you need, leave the rest.
You delivered.
Why would you need
GUARD: There are no shadows under the noonday sun. Words to live by.
GUARD: My poor feet!
CARJA: Those crazy Oseram tried to kill our Sun-King, until the machine rider stopped them cold.
CARJA: It's a bit, uh, frivolous, isn't it?
CARJA: I prefer the one about the Sun-Priest falling in love with a merchant's daughter.
CARJA: I love this bit!
It's you! The one who saved Meridian from that Oseram lunatic!
Damned if you aren't a ray of sun on a dark day.
Would you help me?
If I can, what happened?
Mass murder that's what!
Five night guards shredded like cabbage out there in the quarry.
Five men murdered, how?
Don't know. One was a buddy from before the liberation.
We worked this quarry together as slaves for the mad King.
My friend, may he walk forever in the light, knew how to fight.
Fiends who do this must have had stealth or numbers.
Could machines have killed them?
Don't see how, the quarry is fenced and gated, and I've never seen a Glinthawk do anything like this.
Anything strike you as strange or out of the ordinary?
Well, let's see, uh…
Oh, yeah! Chunks of corpses gushing blood.
Sorry, pressure's getting to me. Not used to murder. Nah, nothing unusual.
Well, except, we've been doing a little blasting lately and Saravad said…
…naw, that's just stupid.
What exactly did Saravad say?
Ah nothing, kept babbling about a pile of rocks out there.
Said he didn't remember it from yesterday.
I told him that this here is a quarry where we move rocks all day.
So rocks getting moved ain't so surprising, lunkhead.
You've been using explosives?
Sure, to clear away bedrock and get to the good stuff.
We do it for a week or so every year, but that's got nothing to do with the dead.
They were torn apart, not blown up.
I know what killed those men.
A machine that attacks from underground.
It's called a Rockbreaker.
Powerful sounds can attract them.
Great. What in the name of the Sun am I supposed to do about that?
Just sit tight. This kind of thing is my specialty.
CARJA: Waste of time, show was better last week.
CARJA: Oh, you're in for a treat, it's quite a show.
Explosives, quarry's been doing a lot of blasting.
That doesn't look like an ordinary rock pile.
Saw me, here we go.
I just gotta tough the storm out.
CARJA: Oh, wonderful.
CARJA: This isn't up to their usual standard.
I've never seen a machine like that, whoa, nor a hunter so bold! Take this.
It's from the quarry stores, but no-one's going to argue that you don't deserve it.
May you walk in the light, friend.
Especially when dealing with what comes up from the ground.
CARJA: It's a bit frivolous, isn't it?
CARJA: Oh, that's nice. Glad I stopped for a bit.
CARJA: My bones are tired, I've been working too damn hard.
OUTLANDER: Success!
Need them soon enough.
Alright.
Took them long enough.
Now they're hunting me.
SHADOW CARJA: One day our Sun-King is here, the next he's gone.
It's like some horrible dream.
MERCHANT: These aren't goods, they'r—
SHADOW CARJA: Nice to have a break, work's been hard lately.
SHADOW CARJA: I imagine they hope to poison young Itamen's mind against his own people. I pray the Sun provides him clarity.
SHADOW CARJA: Now Itamen's been snatched away?
SHADOW CARJA: Move along.
SYLENS, THROUGH FOCUS: The balustrade. It's a short drop from there.
SYLENS: And you needn't worry about the kestrels.
SYLENS: They'll be too busy acting important to pay attention to you.
ALOY: You've gotta be kidding.
SYLENS: Not at all.
ALOY: This is insane.
SYLENS: Hardly.
SYLENS: The other side of the tower, look for a vent.
ALOY: I see you've been here before.
SYLENS: Obviously.